<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jekabs</title>
    <link>http://gritans.lv/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jekabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 12:44:39 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gritans.lv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More Exploitation</title>
      <link>http://gritans.lv/post/more-exploitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 12:44:39 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gritans.lv/post/more-exploitation/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about all of the improbable events that have me who I am now, at this moment. It seems that the decisions that lead to me being in the right place at the right time for events that have the potential to somewhat affect my life&amp;rsquo;s trajectory are not easily discernible at the time of making the decision. Which means that most of my attempts at taking control of where I wish to go have been and will probably continue to be futile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From High School to the Big Leagues - My Experience at Machine Learning Prague</title>
      <link>http://gritans.lv/post/mlprague-2222/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:37:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gritans.lv/post/mlprague-2222/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to Machine Learning Prague 2022 - &amp;ldquo;The biggest European conference about ML AI and Deep Learning.&amp;rdquo; Every year the event attracts a wide range of very interesting speakers mostly from industry, but also those leading cutting edge research on a daily basis.
While the talks were interesting in and of themselves, I also knew that they would be freely and conveniently distributed online after the event meaning that if I was to go in-person, I better have a justification for the money spent and the necessary time off just to travel to and from the Czech Republic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration &amp; Exploitation</title>
      <link>http://gritans.lv/post/exploration-exploitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 10:58:16 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gritans.lv/post/exploration-exploitation/</guid>
      <description>I myself first heard about the concept of exploration vs exploitation in a rationality camp. There, one morning, without any context we were presented with a simple card game, where
 a full deck is non-randomly divided into 4 piles of 13 cards each. Each of the decks is then separately shuffled. Each red card has a value attached to it. Each turn we get to pick a card from whichever pile we desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>http://gritans.lv/post/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 17:26:21 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gritans.lv/post/first/</guid>
      <description>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Jēkabs - a high-school student from Riga State Gymnasium No. 1, Latvia. Academically, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in mathematics, computer science and economics. I particularly enjoy working on projects that require me to combine models and intuitions from at least two of these and many other fields (of which I know too little of to concretely list them). I&amp;rsquo;ve also always liked tinkering with tech, whether that&amp;rsquo;s Lego robots in 2016 , or home automation and computer networks now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
